Sneha Tamhane

Business Analyst

Profile

Work experience in projects across multiple domains with reputed domestic and international clients. Knowledge of Business analysis key concepts, Business analysis planning and monitoring, elicitation and collaboration, Requirements Life Cycle management, Requirement Analysis.

Hands on experience in modeling requirements using UML diagrams such as Use Cases, Activity diagrams. Well versed in facilitating JAD, walk through, surveys, questionnaires, interviews and brain storming sessions. Worked closely with Project stakeholders, SMEs and staff to understand the requirements and business processes.

Analyzing change request and coordinating the changes required with the development team.

Product management (Backlogs: Epics/ Features/ User Stories), Solve product problem.

Experience in designing in Screen Mockups to capture Business and functional specifications.

Bridging the gap in domain understanding between the client and technical team. Coordinating with the stakeholders to translate the business requirements into actual project plan.

Experience in Iterative Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) methodologies such as Agile and Waterfall. Experience in writing Business Requirement documents (BRD), Functional Requirement Document (FRD) (SRS),

Project Scope document.

Experience in documenting existing and new processes through work flow diagrams.

Excellent team facilitator with good communication and interpersonal skills and ability to utilize available resources.

Education

Bachelor's of Business Administration

Certification and Project

OLA Cab management system internship for 1 month.

Best Business Analysis Industry practice workshop for two weeks at COEPD, Pune

Professional Experience

06/2021 – present Pune, India **Business Analyst - 401K**

Automated Data Processing (ADP)

Requirement gathering, elicitation analysis, documenting needs, efforts, budget and resource estimation. Conducting meetings and presentations to share ideas and findings.

Acting as a liaison between business and IT groups, Business Process modeling and product specification.

Worked on change requests, documentation, BRD, FRD, Use cases, test documents, SOPs/User manuals.

Created wireframes, mockups, understanding document, change request and get sign offs. End to end implementation of products.

Preparation of SOP's, product features, activity diagrams, Process flow charts, Epics, User stories, Version control, value preposition and training manuals for knowledge management.

10/2015 – 06/2021 Pune, India **Customer Service Executive/Business Analyst**

Tech Mahindra Business Services

Conducting meetings and presentations to share ideas and findings with the client.

Acting as a liaison between Business and technical team.

Handled the responsibility as an associate BA for the new application being

developed for the customer.

Worked for escalations team handling difficult customers and resolving their issues

on priority.

Updating the client on the progress of the cases, point of contact for the client.

12/2013 - 09/2015

Customer Service Representative

Pune, India

Vodafone shared services India

Dealing with Clients and Customers on day-to-day basis (Initial 6 months).

Handling customer complaints and retaining customers.

Handling confidential company information.

09/2010 - 10/2012

Customer Service Representative

Pune, India

Hutchison Three global services

Interaction with UK customers for Retentions ,billing and payment related queries.

Skills

Technical Skills

Operating Systems - Windows Modeling language - UML 2.0

SDLC Models - Waterfall and Agile Scrum

Documentation and Project Management tool - JIRA, MS Office (Excel, Word and PowerPoint), MS

Project

Modeling tools - MS Visio, Draw.io

Wire framing and proto typing tools - Axure

Sneha Tamhane